Guide to the Alexander Papers 1665-1883 (bulk, 1717-1786) MS 8
New-York Historical Society
- Series 7: Court Papers, 1684-1818
  - Court Papers--Essex County--Civil Cases. M - Z (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Court Papers--Essex County--Criminal Cases (Box 40, Folder 12)
  - Court Papers--Essex County--Dockets (Box 40, Folder 13)
  - Court Papers--Gloucester County--Civil Cases (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Court Papers--Gloucester County--Criminal Cases (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Court Papers--Hunterdon County--Civil Cases (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Court Papers--Hunterdon County--Criminal Cases (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Court Papers--Hunterdon County--Coroner's Juries (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Court Papers--Hunterdon County--Dockets (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Court Papers--Middlesex County--Civil Cases. A - B (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Court Papers--Middlesex County--Civil Cases. C - Farquahar (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Court Papers--Middlesex County--Civil Cases. Fontine - K (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - Court Papers--Middlesex County--Civil Cases. L - Parker (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Court Papers--Middlesex County--Civil Cases. Patton - S (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Court Papers--Middlesex County--Civil Cases. T - Z (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Court Papers--Middlesex County--Criminal Cases (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Court Papers--Middlesex County--Dockets (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Court Papers--Monmouth County--Civil Cases. A - C (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Court Papers--Monmouth County--Civil Cases. D - F (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Court Papers--Monmouth County--Civil Cases. G - O (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Court Papers--Monmouth County--Civil Cases. P - Z (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Court Papers--Monmouth County--Criminal Cases (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Court Papers--Monmouth County--Dockets (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Court Papers--Morris County--Civil Cases (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Court Papers--Morris County--Criminal Cases (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Court Papers--Morris County--Dockets (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Court Papers--Salem County--Civil Cases (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Court Papers--Salem County--Criminal Cases (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Court Papers--Salem County--Coroner's Jury (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Court Papers--Somerset County--Civil Cases. A - Golborn (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Court Papers--Somerset County--Civil Cases. Goodnight - L (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Court Papers--Somerset County--Civil Cases. M - Parker vs. Jennings (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Court Papers--Somerset County--Civil Cases. Parker vs. Lynes - Z (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Court Papers--Somerset County--Criminal Cases (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Court Papers--Somerset County--Coroner's Juries (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Court Papers--Somerset County--Dockets (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Court Papers--Sussex County--Civil Cases (Box 44, Folder 8)
  - Court Papers--Sussex County--Criminal Cases (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Court Papers--Sussex County--Coroner's Jury (Box 44, Folder 10)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey. Deer Trapping and Oyster Poaching (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Court of Chancery. Bainbridge - Bown (No "A") (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Court of Chancery. Brockholst vs. Ryerson (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Court of Chancery. Bull - Burnet (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Court of Chancery. C - DuBois (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Court of Chancery. Creditors of Charles Dunstar vs. Executors of Cherles (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Court of Chancery. E - Mann (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Court of Chancery. Martin vs. Farquahar (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Court of Chancery. Moore - Shotwell (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Court of Chancery. Smith (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Court of Chancery. Steel - van Cortlandt vs. Smith (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Court of Chancery. van Cortlandt vs.Thomases (1 of 3), 1732 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Court of Chancery. van Cortlandt vs.Thomases (2 of 3), 1732 (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Court of Chancery. van Cortlandt vs.Thomases (3 of 3), 1732 (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Court of Chancery. van Mater - White (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Court of Chancery. Dockets (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Supreme Court--Civil Cases. A - Clark (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Supreme Court--Civil Cases. Cooper (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Supreme Court--Civil Cases. Coxe - K (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Supreme Court. L - M (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Supreme Court--Civil Cases. N - Z (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Supreme Court--Criminal Cases (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Supreme Court. Dockets (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Supreme Court. Accounts of Costs by Judicial Term (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Civil Cases. Johnston vs. Coxe (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Dockets. Multiple Counties & Supreme Court (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey--Court of Vice-Admiralty (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Court Papers--Albany County--Civil Cases (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Court Papers--Albany County--Criminal Cases (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Court Papers--King's County--Civil Cases (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Court Papers--New York--Montgomery County--Civil Cases (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Court Papers--New York--Civil Cases. A (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Court Papers--New York--Civil Cases. B - D (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Court Papers--New York--Civil Cases. G - H (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Court Papers--New York--Civil Cases. J - Moors (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Court Papers--New York--Civil Cases. Morris - S (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Court Papers--New York--Civil Cases. T - Z (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Court Papers--New York--Criminal Cases (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Court Papers--New York. Dockets (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Court Papers--New York. Depeyster vs. Prevoost (1 of 3), 1725-1729 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Court Papers--New York. Depeyster vs. Prevoost (2 of 3), 1725-1729 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Court Papers--New York. Depeyster vs. Prevoost (3 of 3), 1725-1729 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Court Papers--New York. Medina vs. Het (1 of 2), 1725 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Court Papers--New York. Medina vs. Het (2 of 2), 1725 (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Court Papers--Orange County--Civil Cases (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Court Papers--Orange County--Criminal Cases (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Court Papers--Orange County. Docket (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Court Papers--Richmond County--Criminal Cases (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Court Papers--Suffolk County--Civil Cases (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Court Papers--Suffolk County--Civil Cases. Nicoll vs. Mills (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Court Papers--Suffolk County--Criminal Cases (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Court Papers--Tryon County--Civil Cases (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Court Papers--Westchester County--Civil Cases (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Court Papers--Westchester County--Civil Cases. Palmer et al. Vs. Cortlandt et al. (1 of 2), 1727 (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Court Papers--Westchester County. Palmer et al. Vs. Cortlandt et al. (2 of 2), 1727 (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Court Papers--Westchester County--Criminal Cases (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Court Papers--New York--Admiralty Court (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Court Papers--New York--Admiralty Court. Kennedy vs. Sloop "Margaret & Mary", 1727 (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Court Papers--New York--Admiralty Court. vanden Closter vs. Owners of Privateers, 1745 (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Court Papers--New York. Second Nine Partners Tract (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - Court Papers--[New York. Second Nine Partners vs. Henry Beekman et al.], 1747-1753 (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Court Papers--New Jersey & New York. Petitions (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Court Papers--Pennsylvania--Civil Cases (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Court Papers--Unidentified Courts, Counties & Colonies--Civil Cases. A - Z by Plaintiff (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Court Papers--Unidentified Counties & Colonies. Dockets (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - Court Papers--Unidentified Counties & Colonies--Coroner's Jury (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Court Papers--Unidentified Counties & Colonies. Unidentified Cases. Memoranda (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Court Papers. Affidavits & Depositions. Unidentified Cases (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Court Papers. Arguments, Briefs, Opinions. Unidentified Cases (1 of 2) (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Court Papers. Arguments, Briefs, Opinions. Unidentified Cases (2 of 2) (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - Court Papers. Bills of Costs. Unidentified Venues & Multiple Cases (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Court Papers. Blank Writs, Summonses, etc. (Box 54, Folder 9)
- Series 8: New Jersey Proprietors, 1707-1797
  Series 8 consists of papers relating to the Proprietors of the respective divisions of the colony of New Jersey, primarily the Eastern Division. The series includes minutes of the Proprietors' meetings, reports, accounts, and memoranda. This material certain aspects of the administration of the proprietorship, including the advertising, surveying, and sale of lands, and the distribution of dividends. Other material concerns the dispute between the Eastern and Western Proprietors over the exact location of the boundary between East and West New Jersey. Also included in this series is the diary (1752-1775) of George Ryerse, who acted as the Eastern Proprietors' agent in Bergen County.
  - New Jersey Proprietors--Eastern Division. Minutes of Meetings, 1745, 1762-1797 (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - New Jersey Proprietors--Eastern Division. Reports and Memoranda, 1741-1787, undated (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - New Jersey Proprietors--Eastern Division. Petitions Received, 1770-1785, undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - New Jersey Proprietors--Eastern Division. Accounts, Bulk 1742-1791 (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - New Jersey Proprietors--Eastern Division. East/West NJ Boundary, 1765-[1784] (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - New Jersey Proprietors--Eastern Division. East/West NJ Boundary. Negotiations with Loyalist Proprietors, 1782 (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - New Jersey Proprietors--Eastern Division. Journal of George Ryerse, 1752-1775 (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - New Jersey Proprietors--Western Division. Minutes and Resolutions, 1717, 1743 (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - New Jersey Proprietors--East & West. Memoranda of Land Transfers, Dividends, Leases, undated (Box 55, Folder 9)
  - New Jersey Proprietors. Disputes Regarding Proprietary Shares, 1773, undated (Box 55, Folder 10)
- Series 9: Colony/State of New Jersey, 1674-1787
  Series 9 consists of papers relating to the colony/state of New Jersey, including drafts of legislation, instructions to personnel of the Surveyor general's office, and copies of commissions issued to colony/state officials.
  - New Jersey. Copies of Extracts from Proprietors' Records, 1707-1775, undated (Box 55, Folder 11)
  - New Jersey. Instructions for Surveyors, 1744, undated (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - New Jersey. Lists of Surveys Completed and Warrants & Deeds Issued, undated (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - New Jersey. Petitions, 1720-1785, undated (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - New Jersey. Drafts of Legislation, 1727-1773, undated (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - New Jersey. Copies of Commissions, 1674-1785 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - New Jersey. Lists of Officials, undated (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - New Jersey. Tax Assessments. Perth Amboy, 1775, 1785-1787 (Box 56, Folder 7)
- Series 10: Colony/State of New York, 1683-1785
  Series 10 consists of papers relating to the colony/state of New York, including drafts of legislation, petitions, material regarding the establishment of the New York - Connecticut boundary (the "Oblong" or "Equivalent Lands") and material regarding the establishment of the New York - New Jersey boundary.
  - New Jersey/New York Boundary, [1717-1773] (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - New York. Oblong or Equivalent Lands. Minutes & Resolutions, 1701, 1730, 1732 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - New York. Oblong or Equivalent Lands. Instructions to New York Commissioners, 1724 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - New York. Oblong or Equivalent Lands. Petitions, 1725, undated (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - New York. Oblong or Equivalent Lands. Answers to Advertisement, undated (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - New York. Oblong or Equivalent Lands. Account Book, undated (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - New York. Oblong or Equivalent Lands. Memoranda, 1724-1741, undated (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - New York. Petitions, undated (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - New York. Drafts of Legislation, 1683, 1732, 1785 (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - New York. Petition of Attorney General Bradley to Gov. Cosby, undated (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - New York. Warrant to James Alexander as N.Y. Attorney General, 1722 (Box 56, Folder 18)
  - New York. List of Tenants in Arrears for Quitrents, 1706, 1721, 1741 (Box 56, Folder 19)
  - New York. Extract from Naturalization Records, 1740 (Box 56, Folder 20)
- Series 11: Business Papers, 1699-1813
  Business Papers are those papers pertaining to the business affairs of persons other than James, William and Mary Alexander. The series contains accounts, bills, receipts, memoranda, etc of a wide variety of persons. Included in the series is material created by or pertaining to a group of New York landowners collectively called the Second Nine Partners, attorney Cortlandt Skinner, the merchant house of McVickar & Hill, New York merchant Robert Snell, and merchants Andrew Bell and Peter Smitzer, both of Perth Amboy, New Jersey. Also in the series are accounts, bills, and receipts whose creators or principals cannot be identified.
  - Business Papers. Estate of Charles Dunstar. Inventory, 1727 (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Business Papers. Estate of Daniel Donaldson Dunstar. Inventories, 1749 (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Business Papers. McVickar & Hill. Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1781, 1786-1787, undated (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Business Papers. McVickar & Hill. Insurance Policy for Sloop "Letitia", 1786 (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Business Papers. Robert Snell. Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1771-1773, undated (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Business Papers. Accounts, Bills, Receipts. Other Persons, 1699-1749, undated (Box 57, Folder 6)
  - Business Papers. Accounts, Bills, Receipts. Other Persons, 1750-1813 (Box 57, Folder 7)
  - Business Papers. Memoranda. Other Persons, undated (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Business Papers. Memoranda. Other Persons, 1720-1810 (Box 57, Folder 9)
  - Business Papers. Invoices. Other Persons, 1724-1749, undated (Box 57, Folder 10)
  - Business Papers. Sight Drafts/Time Drafts. Other Persons, 1725-1805 (Box 57, Folder 11)
  - Business Papers. Accounts, Bills, Receipts. Unknown Persons, undated (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Business Papers. Advertisements for Land, 1745-1800, undated (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Business Papers. Account Books. Andrew Bell, 1784 (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Business Papers. Day Books. Andrew Bell, 1786 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Business Papers. Account Book. Peter Smitzer, 1775-1776 (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Business Papers. Account Books. Peter Smitzer with Peter Barberi, 1775-1776 (Box 58, Folder 6)
- Series 12: Miscellaneous Items, 1712-[1883]
  The remainder of the collection consists of historical notes, genealogical material that appears to have been compiled in the 1880's by an unidentified person, a manuscript regarding vendue sales, author unidentified, probably dating from the last quarter of the 18th century, and fragments.
  - Remarks on Vendue Sales. Author Unknown, undated (Box 58, Folder 7)
  - Genealogy of James Alexander's Descendants, [1883] (Box 58, Folder 8)
  - [Historical Notes on New Netherland], undated (Box 58, Folder 9)
  - Fragments of Architectural Sketches, undated (Box 58, Folder 10)
  - Fragments, undated (Box 58, Folder 11)
  - Oversize Legal Papers (not foldered), 1712, 1720, 1727, 1733 (Box 59)
  - Oversize Legal Papers (not foldered), 1737, 1739, 1754 (Box 60)